hey everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist and we are still
talking about our top 10 Tosca best
practices
now we have already discussed about
three best practices and I'm going to
talk about the fourth best practice in
this complete list now if you have not
watched the previous best practices
again you know the drill go back and
watch all the three best practices and
make sure you have implemented them
before continuing with this particular
video
also don't forget to subscribe to our
channel so that you don't miss out on
all the upcoming videos on this
particular topic
so now let's talk about this particular
best practice it's a very common best
practice which is followed in test
automation no matter which tool you use
or which framework you use okay
so it basically talks about not using
any static weights in your automated
test cases and the reason is very simple
when you use static weights then your
test cases are going to take more time
to execute because static weights are
wait times which are constant which
means the system or the tool is going to
wait for that amount of time no matter
what is the state of the application or
what you intended to get from the
application is already present right so
maybe you don't need to wait for that
amount of time but since you are using a
static fit the system will always wait
for that amount of time before
proceeding with the next step in your
test case and that's the biggest
disadvantage because if you keep on
adding the static weights in your test
cases then your overall execution time
for that particular test case will
increase by a lot of time okay
so instead of this you should always be
using a dynamic weight mechanism which
can basically synchronize your
application with your automation tool
and that is the same thing which is
applied in Tosca
so there are number of ways to do this
but generally when you want to
synchronize your application with Tosca
and you want to apply some weight
mechanism then you should be using the
weight on method now it is uh one of the
action modes okay and we'll see how it
is done but this is the method which you
should use because it is dynamic in
nature so it will wait
um until a specified amount of time okay
which is specified in the test case or
in the settings and then uh it will wait
until that maximum time but the
difference between static weight and the
weight on method is that when you use
weight on method then it will only wait
for the time until that particular
condition which you have specified is
met
so once that condition is met it will go
ahead and it will execute the next step
no matter even if it has not reached or
not waited the amount of time it should
wait for that maximum period right so
you can see the difference uh one is
dynamic in nature one is static in
nature okay and for static weight we use
the t-box weight method okay
so we'll see both the methods with an
example okay and for this example I'm
going to use one of the obstacle pages
okay here you can see uh this in this
obstacle you need to click on the button
calculate automatically after some time
the send button will be visible or
enabled so right now it is disabled and
I cannot click on this but if I click on
calculate and then it is going to take
this progress bar till 100
uh so you need to wait for this progress
bar to complete hundred percent and then
only the send button will be enabled and
then I can click on this to complete
this obstacle right so that's the job
you need to do
but uh there are two ways of doing this
okay so one is the inefficient way where
you can use a t-box wheat method to wait
for this amount of time and also you
need to calculate how much time it is
taking to reach 100 percent right
so it may be 20 seconds 30 seconds and
similarly you have to wait it in your
you need to put a wait time in your test
case Okay after which this will be
enabled and then you can click on it so
this is the inefficient way of
automating this particular scenario the
efficient way is to click on calculate
and then put a weight on action method
on this send button okay so it will wait
till the send button is enabled no
matter how much time it takes okay
and once it is enabled then we click on
this so this is the efficient way of
automating the scenario with Tosca okay
now let's see uh this in action okay so
I have already created two obstacle test
cases for this particular scenario okay
and uh it is the same scenario okay but
the way I'm doing it is little different
so if you look at the first way it is
using the key box with method here the
duration I've specified it as 20 seconds
I don't really know exactly how much
time it takes but I have put a certain
time so that it will wait for 20 seconds
okay after clicking on calculate and
then it will click on the send button
okay
the second method is uh doing the same
but it doesn't have the t-box feet a
step okay so one last step
also if you see in this particular step
it clicks on calculate and then it is
using the action mode weight on to wait
till this particular condition is
satisfied in the value which is enabled
equals equals true okay and then it will
click on calculate
so you can see the difference here there
is one uh step lesser okay also it is
more efficient because I don't need to
calculate the time it has to wait and in
real time applications okay the wait
time could be anything it could depend
on your network bandwidth or it could
depend on various other reasons so it is
practically impossible to actually
calculate a particular time uh you
should wait for a particular control to
appear or enable also you should not be
doing that you should be making your
test cases more dynamic in nature so
that it can handle this kind of
scenarios if they appear during the
execution where you don't have any
control over your test cases okay
so if I go ahead and run this you will
see the difference okay so let me run it
the first time where we are using a
static weight and it is going to wait
till uh 20 seconds after it clicks on
the calculate button okay
so here it is clicking on the calculate
button and then it is waiting for 20
seconds no matter if the progress is
complete still it is going to wait for
that amount of time you can see here it
is still not clicking on the same button
because maybe my wait time is more than
what it should be okay
and sometimes you will not even get the
desired result as you can see here now
this particular page has gone back to
its original state so it didn't even
click the send button okay so I need to
adjust my time wait time to basically
sync with this particular
functionality okay which is very
difficult and which is not recommended
now let's try and run the second test
case okay and let's see the difference
and this time around you will see that
even if I am not using any wait time it
is able to progress and it is able to
click on the send button okay because it
is dynamic it can wait until the amount
of time uh till that send button is not
enabled okay and as soon as it is
enabled it is going to click on it it's
not going to wait any longer okay
so you can see here the send button got
enabled and then I was able to click on
it
so you can see the difference
um one is more efficient and gives you
better results you would be sure that
using a dynamic weight you are actually
performing the right kind of action
which your automated test case is
supposed to do but in static weight it
might pass sometimes it might feel uh
many times okay so you know the
difference but this is the best practice
which is recommended by transientists so
to conclude uh you should only be using
static weight as a last resort
so if nothing else works then only go
ahead and use static weight but this
should be the minimum in your test cases
okay
uh always try to use the dynamic weight
mechanisms one way is the weight on
method there could be several other ways
in Tosca through which you can implement
this Dynamic weight okay
so that's all for this particular video
um and talking about the best practices
uh hope you like it and you enjoyed it
we have lots more videos coming up so
keep watching and keep learning